In this tutorial video, we use the 11th version of Doshi Marvelous Designer.
If you need to learn the 10th version of Marvelous Designer, please watch the previous video.
In order to make it easier to learn, the Doshi Marvelous Designer is used in this tutorial.
Now let's learn how to create a template in 2D window.
First of all, we need to import a virtual model.
In this tutorial video, we will use Feifei from FemaleVR.
Stop your mouse on the multidirectional tool, and select the rectangle tool after clicking on the drop-down menu.
Start from the center of the model, hold down the left mouse button and drag the mouse.
Draw a rectangle according to the body shape of the virtual model, and send the mouse to the appropriate position.
Change the texture display type to semi-transparent surface.
Now you can adjust the template by using the virtual model screenshot.
When the mouse is stuck on the tool, click on Add Marker on the lower left.
In the line in front, at the lowest position of the ruler and the highest position of the line,
Press the left mouse button separately to add 2 points.
Then add 1 point at the bottom of the page.
Just make sure that there are some points below the bottom of the model screenshot,
rather than the one below the model screenshot.
Then select the tool of editing HTML,
When we have confirmed these points, we can delete the excess points.
And this point on the outside of the shoulder, we adjust it according to the angle of the shoulder line.
Please note that this shoulder line is as parallel to the model's shoulder as possible,
which helps to create a more harmonious clothing pattern.
Next, let's draw the collar and sleeve curve lines.
In the drop-down menu, find the editor curve point tool,
click on the straight line to create a curve point.
Drag the curve point to adjust the corner of the collar and other panels as a straight line,
so that it will become a smooth curve when pasting other panels.
Use the same method to draw the sleeve curve,
and also maintain the corner of the collar as a straight line.
You can increase the curve point to adjust the details.
The sleeve curve line is shaped into a straight line,
and the upper curve is more flat, and the bottom curve is obvious.
Now we have completed one side of the front panel.
Please select the adjustment panel tool.
On this panel, click on the mouse button on the right and select copy.
On the right,
click on the empty place in the background and select mirror pasting.
Next, we will modify this mirror pasting panel to the back panel.
In the previous tutorial of the 3D window of the creation panel,
we have mentioned that the collar of the back panel is a little lighter than the front panel.
First, use the editor curve tool to increase the center point of the back neck,
and then use the editor curve point tool to adjust the shape of the back collar.
Due to the back curve of the person,
the curve of the back curve is more flat,
and it is not like the front panel to consider the impact of the chest.
The sleeve curve of the back panel is more flat compared to the front panel,
and the curve of the curve of the bottom curve is shorter,
and the curve is also larger.
In the tool group of the editor panel,
find the editor curve tool in the menu,
click and drag the curve to follow the video to complete the adjustment.
You can also use the editor curve point tool to complete the adjustment.
Next, let's learn how to create a sleeve panel.
Let's learn how to create a sleeve panel.
Select the rectangle tool and draw a half-sleeved sleeve panel.
Draw a rectangle that is wider than the arm,
the length can be customized,
then use the adjustment panel tool to rotate it to the parallel position of the arm,
and align the highest point to the sharp point.
Select the plus point line tool,
add a point near the bottom of the page.
After completion, switch to the adjustment panel tool,
right-click on the panel,
select Rotate X-axis,
then click on the bottom to rotate the panel back.
Now we can delete the excess points.
Now we will use the editor curve tool to adjust the sleeve panel line.
Please add curve points and adjust according to the effect in the video.
The front sleeve panel line is usually from top to bottom,
first protruding and then arching,
the point is in the middle position.
Now we are going to adjust the curve,
we have completed half of the sleeve panel,
use the edit panel tool,
right-click on the middle line,
select Open,
the panel will open along this line.
Please note that because the sleeve itself is not a symmetrical shape,
so here we choose to open,
instead of opening the editor in a symmetrical way.
Think about our previous panels,
compared to the front panel,
the back panel will be wider,
and the curve point will be a little lower.
So we need to choose the edit panel tool,
adjust the sleeve panel line.
When modifying the sleeve panel line,
we can move the front panel's curve points inwards a little bit,
to narrow down the width of the sleeve on this side.
On the contrary,
for the back panel,
we need to move the curve point of the protruding curve line outwards,
to widen the width of the sleeve on this side.
And the curve point from the protruding curve line to the arching curve line,
is about one-third to one-fourth of the sleeve panel,
and the back panel is about one-third to one-fourth of the sleeve panel.
Now a sleeve panel is completed.
After we finish the curve line,
we can adjust more details.
Choose the edit panel tool,
right-click on each panel,
and select the column symmetrical panel,
panel and curve line,
and then click OK.
When a panel is in a symmetrical relationship,
modify one of the panels,
and the other panel will also be symmetrical.
When moving the symmetrical panel from the curve,
press the Shift key to place the panel in the horizontal direction.
Do the same for the back panel and the sleeve panel.
Next, let's make the chest pocket.
Select the mouse on the multidirectional tool,
and then select the rectangle tool in the drop-down menu.
In the 3D window,
click on the appropriate position,
and then you can use the blue reference point that appears at the same time in the 2D window,
to draw the pocket line.
The two front panels will also appear in the internal rectangle,
because there is a symmetrical relationship between these two panels.
These internal rectangles are the seam positions of the pockets.
Next, we are going to remove the pocket panel,
and select the mouse on the edit panel tool,
and then select the pocket line in the drop-down menu.
In the frame selection,
the internal rectangle is right-clicked on the selected position,
and then select the pocket panel.
Please note that the pocket panel is not symmetrical,
but an independent panel.
Now that we have completed the creation of the T-shirt panel,
please save this project as a project file.
In the follow-up tutorial,
we will learn how to arrange and separate these panels
to complete the complete costume.
In the next video,
we will learn how to do it.
In this video,
So,
thanks for watching.
See you in the next video.
Thank you for watching.
Bye-bye.